I was here about four years ago,
كنت هنا منذ حوالي اربع سنوات ,
talking about the relationship of design and happiness.
اتحدث عن علاقة فن التصميم بالسعادة.
At the very end of it, I showed a list under that title.
وفي نهاية المحاضرة, عرضت قائمة تحت هذا العنوان.
I learned very few things in addition since
لم اتعلم إلا اشياء قليلة جدا منذ ذلك الحين --
(Laughter) --
(ضحك)
but made a whole number of them into projects since.
ولكني نفذتها كلها في مشاريع بعد ذلك.
These are inflatable monkeys in every city in Scotland:
هذه قرود قابلة للنفخ في كل مدينة في اسكتلندا--
"Everybody always thinks they are right."
"كل شخص يعتقد دائما انه على حق"
They were combined in the media.
تم جمعها في وسائل الإعلام.
"Drugs are fun in the beginning but become a drag later on."
"الادوية متعة في البداية ولكنها تصبح عبء فيما بعد."
We're doing changing media.
نحن نغيّر الإعلام.
This is a projection that can see the viewer
هذه شاشة عرض تستطيع رؤية المشاهِد
as the viewer walks by.
عندما يمر المشاهِد.
You can't help but actually ripping that spider web apart.
لا بد له من تمزيق شبكة العنكبوت.
All of these things are pieces of graphic design.
كل هذه الاشياء هي اجزاء من تصميم الجرافيك.
We do them for our clients.
نصممها لأجل زبائننا.
They are commissioned.
بتكليف منهم.
I would never have the money to actually pay for the installment
لن املك ابداً المال الكافي لدفع تكاليف تركيبها
or pay for all the billboards or the production of these,
أو لدفع قيمة لوحات الاعلان أو قيمة الانتاج,
so there's always a client attached to them.
هناك دائما زبون يتكفل بها.
These are 65,000 coat hangers in a street
هناك 65,000 من علاّقات المعاطف في شارع
that's lined with fashion stores.
مليء بمحلات الازياء.
"Worrying solves nothing."
"الخوف لا يحل شيئا."
"Money does not make me happy"
"المال لا يجعلني سعيدا"
appeared first as double-page spreads in a magazine.
ظهرت اولا على مساحة صفحتين كاملتين في مجلة.
The printer lost the file, didn't tell us.
الطابعة فقدت الملف, ولم تُخبرنا.
When the magazine -- actually, when I got the subscription --
المجلة عندما ـ في الواقع,عندما استلمت العدد
it was 12 following pages.
كان هناك 12 صفحة
It said, "Money does does make me happy."
تقول," المال يجعلني يجعلني سعيداً."
And a friend of mine in Austria felt so sorry for me
صديق لي في النمسا, شعر بالأسف من أجلي
that he talked the largest casino owner in Linz
فأقنع مالك اكبر كازينو في مدينة لينز
into letting us wrap his building.
بأن يجعلنا نغلّف مبناه
So this is the big pedestrian zone in Linz.
هذه منطقة المشاة الرئيسيه في لينز
It just says "Money," and if you look down the side street,
وهي فقط تقول"المال," واذا نظرت الى الشارع الجانبي,
it says, "does not make me happy."
تقول, "لا يجعلني سعيدا."
We had a show that just came down last week in New York.
كان لدينا عرض, في نيويورك الاسبوع الماضي.
We steamed up the windows permanently,
قمنا بتغبيش النوافذ بالبخار,
and every hour we had a different designer come in
وفي كل ساعة كان يدخل مصمم مختلف
and write these things that they've learned into the steam in the window.
ويكتب تلك الامور التي تعلمها على نوافذ البخار.
Everybody participated -- Milton Glaser,
الكل شارك .."ميلتون جلاسر".
Massimo Vignelli.
ماسيمو فينيلي.
Singapore was quite in discussion.
سنغافورة كانت في نقاش.
This is a little spot that we filmed there
هذه بقعة صغيرة قمنا بتصويرها هناك
that's to be displayed on the large JumboTrons in Singapore.
ليتم عرضهاعلى شاشة العرض الكبيرة"JumboTrons" في سنغافورة,
And, of course, it's one that's dear to my heart,
وبالطبع هذه عزيزه على قلبي,
because all of these sentiments --
بسبب كل هذه العواطف,
some banal, some a bit more profound --
بعضها كان بسيطاً, وبعضها كان اعمق قليلا,
all originally had come out of my diary.
كلها اصلا خرجَت من يومياتي.
And I do go often into the diary
وانا ارجع كثيرا الى يومياتي
and check if I wanted to change something about the situation.
و ارى ما إذا كنت اريد تغيير شي عن الوضع.
If it's -- see it for a long enough time,
ان كانت.. أراها لوقت طويل بما فيه الكفايه,
I actually do something about it.
فانا في الواقع أفعل شي حيالها.
And the very last one is a billboard.
واخر المشاريع هو لوحة اعلانات.
This is our roof in New York, the roof of the studio.
هذا هو سطحنا في نيويورك, سطح الاستديو.
This is newsprint plus stencils that lie on the newsprint.
هذه مخطوطات ملقاة على ورق طباعة الصحف.
We let that lie around in the sun.
تركناها ملقاة تحت الشمس
As you all know, newsprint yellows significantly in the sun.
كما تعرفون جميعا, ورق طباعة الصحف يتحول للون الاصفر بفعل الشمس.
After a week, we took the stencils and the leaves off,
بعد اسبوع, أزلنا المخطوطات واوراق الشجر,
shipped the newsprints to Lisbon to a very sunny spot,
قمنا بشحن ورق الطباعه الى "لشبونه" في بقعة مشمسه,
so on day one the billboard said,
في اليوم الاْول تقول لوحة الإعلانات,
"Complaining is silly. Either act or forget."
"الشكوى سخيفة.إما تصرّف او انسى."
Three days later it faded, and a week later,
بعد ثلاثة أيام بهت لونها, وبعد أسبوع,
no more complaining anywhere.
لا مزيد من الشكوى على أي حال.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Thank you so much.
شكراً جزيلاً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)